
Execute native commands to your database

This command takes as input a datasource defined in prisma.config.ts and a script, using --stdin or --file.
The script input parameters are mutually exclusive, only 1 must be provided.

The output of the command is connector-specific, and is not meant for returning data, but only to report success or failure.

On SQL databases, this command takes as input a SQL script.
The whole script will be sent as a single command to the database.

This command is currently not supported on MongoDB.

Usage

  $ prisma db execute [options]

  The datasource URL configuration is read from the Prisma config file (e.g., prisma.config.ts).

Options

-h, --help            Display this help message
--config              Custom path to your Prisma config file

Script input, only 1 must be provided:
--file                Path to a file. The content will be sent as the script to be executed

Flags

--stdin              Use the terminal standard input as the script to be executed

Examples

  Execute the content of a SQL script file using the datasource configured in prisma.config.ts
  $ prisma db execute --file ./script.sql

  Execute the SQL script from stdin using the configured datasource
  $ echo 'TRUNCATE TABLE dev;' | \
    prisma db execute \
    --stdin

